Amer Fathullah Nuaim Zakaria

FULL STACK DEVELOPER · ML ENGINEER

Lot 5614 Kg Baru Bukit Changung, Manir, 21200 Kuala Terengganu, Terengganu

🛮 (+60) 10-575-2992 | 💌 amerfathullah@gmail.com | 🖸 amerfathullah | 🛅 amerfathullah

"Trust the process."

Summary.

Junior Full Stack Developer at fin-tech company TFX Islamic Sdn Bhd. Have developed the procurement module which is a part of the Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) project in the company. 2+ years of diverse software engineering experience such as front-end development, back-end development, mobile development and machine learning.

Love to work in a team, continuous learning and agile environment. Interested in writing cleaner code, devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools.

Work Experience

TFX Islamic Sdn. Bhd.Petaling Jaya, Selangor

JUNIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Jun. 2022 - Present

- Develop front-end and back-end modules for ERP platform.
- Gather the requirements and discuss the system workflow of the Procurement module with the stakeholder.
- Design and develop the entire workflow of the Procurement module based on the requirements of the stakeholder.
- Maintain staging and production environment in Amazon Web Services (AWS).
- Maintain and debug the code of other modules in the ERP project. Refactored the code to improve the performance of data filtering from the database for documentation and reporting purposes.
- Designing and developing the inventory management module to keep track of the stock in and out transfer, restock count from goods received notes and sales from invoices. Display it on a month-to-date and year-to-date basis.
- · Undertake other duties of similar nature as reasonably required by the immediate supervisor from time to time.

CEFS Response Kerteh, Terengganu

TECHNICAL REVIEW & COMMUNICATION EXECUTIVE

Mar. 2022 - May. 2022

- Developed mobile apps for digitization and automation of company work process.
- · Negotiated and discussed with vendors and contractors that supply company equipment
- · Participated in industrial firefighting and wild animal capture training.
- Reviewed the equipment inspection report at every plant monthly as scheduled.
- Liaised with the procurement department to issue purchase orders for expired or insufficient equipment in the company premises and issued purchase requisitions to buy new equipment for company uses.
- · Diagnosed and performed services for faulty equipment in the company, especially surveillance equipment.

Skymind CNS Sdn. Bhd.

Georgetown, Penang

FRONTEND ENGINEER & JUNIOR AI ENGINEER

Jan. 2021 - Dec. 2021

- · Developed the front-end of an Al-based security camera monitoring system that detects potential dangers across multiple video footage.
- Developed the front-end of Vpass website, an Al-based web application to facilitate contact tracing efforts in response to the COVID-19 pandemic in Malaysia.
- · Implemented multiple third-party API services for SMS two-factor authentication email notifications for Vpass website.
- Developed Vpass administration dashboard that employer uses to keep track of and monitor the COVID-19 status of their employees within their company.
- Developed a dashboard for Vpass pharmacists to handle false positive results of Vpass COVID-19 test kit that needs to be verified manually by the human eye. The false positive results are then sent to the AI model for retraining purposes.
- Researched reinforcement learning algorithms suitable for smart traffic light systems to reduce traffic congestion problems at the traffic light using a traffic simulation program.
- Researched and developed an AI model using machine learning or deep learning to detect vehicles and simulate them in an open-world simulation program.
- Wrote documentation on the research methodology and approach when training the AI models, specifically in the field of machine learning in computer vision.
- Became a mentor for an Artificial Intelligence Graduate Employability Training (AI-GET) program, a program that teaches the interested individual to learn the basics of Machine Learning in Computer Vision.

Sapura Thales Electronics Sdn. Bhd.

Ampang, Selangor

CUSTOMER SERVICE ENGINEER INTERN

Jun. 2019 - Aug. 2019

• Learned and developed the front-end and back-end of an inventory management system that tracks and monitors the repair history of the company's products using PHP and MySQL.

University Project

(Final Year Project) Integrated Web & Mobile App Based KOE Venue Reservation

- A system that facilitates the venue reservation process in Kulliyyah of Engineering, IIUM Gombak.
- Technologies used: Ionic framework, Typescript, Firebase.

Arduino-Based Smart Health Monitoring System

- · A smart system that monitors the patients remotely and will send warning signals if the patient's health deteriorates.
- · Technologies used: Arduino.

Online Ratings for Electronic Gadgets for Commercial Purpose

- · An electronic rating review analysis using Support Vector Machine and Multinomial Naïve Bayes algorithms.
- Technologies used: Python, scikit-learn, Machine Learning.

IIUM Runner Website

- A system that handles customers' requests for IIUM runner.
- Technologies used: Laravel framework, PHP, MySQL.

Honors & Awards

UNIVERSITY AWARDS

2019/2020 Dean's List , International Islamic University of Malaysia	Semester 2
2019/2020 Dean's List , International Islamic University of Malaysia	Semester 1
2018/2019 Dean's List , International Islamic University of Malaysia	Semester 1
2017/2018 Dean's List , International Islamic University of Malaysia	Semester 2

Certificates

2022

	3 · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · ·	
2022	Flutter & Dart - The Complete Guide [2022 Edition], Udemy	

Build an app with ASPNET Core and Angular from scratch, Udemv

2021 **Graduate Engineer**, Board of Engineers Malaysia

2021 Artificial Intelligence from Data Perspective, CertifAl 27396017
2021 Certified Engineer in Computer Vision, CertifAl 26599895

Education

International Islamic University of Malaysia

Gombak, Selangor

B.E. (Hons) IN ELECTRONICS-COMPUTER INFORMATION

Jul. 2016 - Aug. 2020

• Member and committee of multiple clubs and communities such as Art Club, E-Sports Community, Capoeira Club.

Centre for Foundation Studies, IIUM

Petaling Jaya, Selangor

FOUNDATION IN ENGINEERING

May. 2015 - Jun. 2016

• Foundation studies in preparation to enter university.

Skills_

Programming Language

 Flutter, Python, Scikit-learn, Java, OpenCV, DL4J, C++, JavaScript, AngularJS, ReactJS, HTML, MySQL, PHP, Laravel, PyTorch, TensorFlow, sumo, Carla, Ionic, Typescript

Hardware

· Arduino, Altera Quartus, Eagle PCB

Other Software/Tools

• Deep Learning, Machine Learning, Computer Vision